<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Matthew Trask</title>
    <link href="https://matthewtrask.net" />
    <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/feed.atom" />
    <updated>2019-08-12T22:40:23+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/feed.atom</id>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
                <entry>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/how-I-got-into-cycling</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/how-I-got-into-cycling" />
    <title>How I got into cycling.</title>
    <published>2019-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">The picture above is my view when Im riding. Yes I have teal bar tape, I love it. The Garmin has been a godsend. I get my heart rate, heart rate zone, speed, average speed, cadence and distance all right there. 
That&#039;s amazing, congratulations! I picked......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>The picture above is my view when Im riding. Yes I have teal bar tape, I love it. The Garmin has been a godsend. I get my heart rate, heart rate zone, speed, average speed, cadence and distance all right there. </p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">That's amazing, congratulations! I picked up cycling this year. It's an awesome sport. Just did way less miles.<br>Would be interesting to read more about your experience. Were you cycling before or started this year? What keeps you motivated? Has it changed something in your life?</p>— Andi Rückauer (@arueckauer) <a href="https://twitter.com/arueckauer/status/1160408216536276992?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 11, 2019</a></blockquote>
<p>Andi sent me this reply after I posted that I was close to crossing the 1,400 miles (2253.082 kilometers) mark. That is 1,400 miles in one year. I didn't really get started til about April with the weather and the fact Nashville gets hosed by the EST/CST date line. Because we are so close to the EST but in CST, we lose daylight quickly in the winter. Which means its harder to ride til about March after work. Since Im on this blog spree, I loved his questions and felt it was a good topic. I talk about cycling <em>alot</em> as a lot of people know. I love it so much. It has given me a way to explore, meet cool people, challenge myself, and make some extra money!</p>
<h3>What keeps me motivated.</h3>
<p>The motivation can be tough at times. My legs will be sore, my back from being in an aggressive riding position, my feet from my shoes, but I still get out there as much as I can. What motivates me is that with things like Strava, and the group I ride with, I see tangiable improvement each time. I don't go out every ride ready to crush PR's or drop anyone in my path, but just based on fitness levels I can tell even easy rides get easier. Or as they say in the group: &quot;it doesn't get easier, you just get faster&quot;. The group rides give me a sense of belonging. Im not the fittest one, the fastest one, or the cutest one (debatable really), but I give it my all, and when we regroup in the middle or at the end of the ride, we congratulate each other for the effort. They see me get crushed on a hill, and they still recognize I gave it my all. It means a lot someone would care to give me that recognition. We share a beer at the end of the night, and talk about things cycling related, or not. I may get my ass kicked on a ride one week, and the next week be at the front of the paceline helping others draft behind me. Its amazing what time will do. </p>
<p>But besides the group, its a sense of exploration. Nashville is rich in greenways that make you feel like you are 50 miles outside of a city, when really I'm only 5 miles away. It's great to be in nature, watching deer play, seeing a turtle still trying to finish the race. Seeing kids learning how to balance while you ride by and they look at you as a source of &quot;I can do that!&quot; is worth it. And yes, it is fun to drop someone on the greenway. I do it a lot. Its a small sense of pride when I can tuck in, drop a gear and hammer it out. </p>
<p>The other thing that motivates me is that I'm helping others learn how to ride in the roads next to cars. When I do bike tours, we ride on normal roads, and these are people who wouldn't normally ride in a road if they could help it. To give them that sense of accomplishment is worth it. </p>
<h3>How I got started.</h3>
<p>I got started with cycling in this form about 4 years ago when I worked for the wonderful <a href="https://twitter.com/jacqueswoodcock">Jacques Woodcock</a>. I saw a tweet of his about him riding in the Tour de Nash here in Nashville and started to ask questions. I've always been attracted to the idea of biking everywhere. I'd love to live in a city where I can do that. It's hard to do it in Nashville because of the heat and lack of bike infrastructure such as bike rooms and showers in offices. No one wants to hang out with the sweaty dude in the office. Its a fact of life. </p>
<p>After some talking with Jacques, I bought my first bike. It was a hybrid bike, nothing special but it was mine. I felt so cool in the streets of Atlanta where really I had no idea what I was doing. I wasn't in a group, I was just on my own. Jacques convinced me to come up to Nashville with him to do a metric century. A metric century consisted of a 64 mile/100 kilometer ride, this one up in Clarksville TN but most of it in the backwoods of Kentucky. I trained hard for it, trying to ride as much as I could. Being a remote job, Jacques told me to use my lunch time as a time to go ride, so I would set out every day around 12pm and just ride til about 1pm and get back to work. It was magical. </p>
<p>When that job ended, I moved up to Nashville. My first week there Jacques punished me with some brutal riding. A tour of Nashville, a brutal 1800 ft of climbing and exploring this new city of mine. From there, I just fell face first into this new hobby. I started reading up on how to get faster, how to get stronger. I watched maintainence videos to learn the basics. From there I found my first group, the slow ride on Wednesdays. They were a group aimed at getting more people riding, more people comfortable with road riding and group riding. It was a great introduction but as I got better I wanted more. I found a ride at the sister shop of the one that did the slow ride and thats where I am now. This group <em>rides</em>. 20mph average, climbing around 1400 ft on average, and a solid mix of riders. Crit riders, distance riders, sprinters and people who do this for fun. I can't recommend a group ride enough. The friendships are enough to make it amazing. </p>
<h3>Has it changed my life?</h3>
<p>God, yes. Unfortunately for my girlfriend, I won't stop talking about rides I've done. She is a trooper and puts up with it. However, I don't know what life would be like if I didn't have my bike. I use it to clear my head after a long day, I use it to get outside and exercise, and I use it to explore. I have a challenge now to ride a bike in all 50 states. I've got 6 down, with plenty more to do. I've gotten my dad into cycling. Funny enough it started with him just doing the 8 mile GA 400 Century while I did the 50 mile edition. It ended with him wanting more. He even messaged me the other day asking to move from standard pedals to the clip ones. It may have saved my parent's marriage too, because it got my dad to become active and focus on his mental health. </p>
<p>It's no understatement that cycling is huge to me. I advocate for more people to ride bikes. The Happiness Institute in Denamark has found people are happier on bikes. I can personally attest to that. Im happiest on a bike. Sure Im happy around friends, but have you cycled with friends?! One of my favorite memories is the ride I did in Miami with 9/10 friends <a href="https://twitter.com/michaelmoussa">Michael Moussa</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/kasiazein">Kat Zien</a> a day before Sunshine PHP where we took a 40 mile ride through Miami. It hurt, it was rough at times but damn it was so much fun. </p>
<p>So what is stopping you? Grab a bike! You will be happier, and when we meet, we can ride instead of just sitting at a bar!</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/from-layoff-to-employed-in-a-week-and-a-half</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/from-layoff-to-employed-in-a-week-and-a-half" />
    <title>How I went from being laid off to employed in a week in a half.</title>
    <published>2019-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">It&#039;s never a good feeling to see people from other offices show up unannouced. It definitely isn&#039;t good if they show up a little doom and gloom with a stack of papers. If you haven&#039;t been through this, use this post as a guideline to take the steps you......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>It's never a good feeling to see people from other offices show up unannouced. It definitely isn't good if they show up a little doom and gloom with a stack of papers. If you haven't been through this, use this post as a guideline to take the steps you need before this happens. If you have, or you are in an unfulfilling job, by all means please use my experiences here to help you get to a job that is fulfilling and meaningful. Life is too short to do work that is mindless and not inspiring to you. As I talked previously, I spent the first half of this year doing a lot of rediscovery about myself, what makes me happy. What I realized was while there were a lot of good challenges at my old job, I never felt fulfilled by it. I yearned for something more. I wanted to make a difference. However, when you have a consistent paycheck coming in, it is hard to break the cycle. When your bills are paid, you are saving and investing (Buy all the <a href="https://investor.vanguard.com/mutual-funds/profile/vtsax">VTSAX</a> you can. Ask me more about this!) and you are able to do things like travel, eat out, and not worry about losing anything, you can easily get stuck. This happened at my old job. When they came to tell us the office was closing, I was a mix of emotions. I was sad I was losing my job, sad I was losing my main income stream, but also indifferent. I knew I would land on my feet, that wasn't a problem. The problem was where would I, how long would it take, and what can I do in the intermediary stages. </p>
<p>I did what any good, mildly depressed person would do: I went home, bought Avengers Endgame, put it on, cuddled with my dog and just chilled. I told myself 24 hours to feel like a failure was good enough. I dont even know if I took the full 24 hours because later that night I was out in the group riding as hard as I could. In fact I feel bad because no one I was riding with knew what was happening, but the group I led ended up getting dragged across the route because I had energy to burn and I made the road and hills in Nashville my bitch. </p>
<p>Now here I am, 11 days later, offer signed and a job starting in a few weeks. How did I do it? More importantly, how can you do it too? Quick thanks to my really good friend <a href="https://twitter.com/michaelmoussa">Michael Moussa</a> for inspiring this post.</p>
<h3>Step One - The Community</h3>
<p>Right after the announcement, but prior to leaving the office for the last time, I sent a quick tweet out. </p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Well, all good things come to an end. <br><br>Im now looking for my next challenge. Got something fun? Send it my way. Nashville or remote. Could relocate for the right challenge! <br><br>RT Please? :)</p>— matt trask (@matthewtrask) <a href="https://twitter.com/matthewtrask/status/1156221503576444928?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 30, 2019</a></blockquote>
<p>The tweet above went gangbusters! I never expected it. However, I can tell you this: ever since I got involved with programming, and the PHP community, I have put my heart into this community to try and help it get better and more awesome for people coming up behind me. From organizing user groups to conferences, speaking, mentoring, podcasting and OSS, I spend <em>hours</em> a week working on this thing. I try my hardest to support everyone in our community when they need help. I don't have the biggest network, but every retweet helps someone get to where they need to be. And I think part of my success is that while I can be an asshole, I can be grumpy, I can be overly sarcastic, I also have empathy, I have understanding and I will use my voice to help others. Because of that, I have cultivated a community that is willing to help me when I need it. </p>
<p>First tip: <strong>grow your community, and keep tending to it. It will die without work. And don't be a raging dickbag to others.</strong></p>
<h3>Step Two - Be open</h3>
<p>What is funny about that is that I just started dating someone, so I was hoping not to relocate but here is my second tip: <strong>Don't be picky, cast a wide net</strong>. </p>
<p>The thing about layoffs is you will usually get a severance. That is great, until you realize the money will dry up eventually. You may get a few weeks at most, never more than 2 months in an office layoff. This could be different with optional layoffs before they become a cost saving measure. That combined with whatever money you have affords you <em>some pickiness</em> but that pickiness could cost you up front. I wanted the widest possible net to catch jobs, so I opened myself to <em>everything</em>. Laravel, Symfony, no framework, Typescript, Rails, I took it all. Do I want to do Rails work? No, but its good interview practice. People would ask me if I preferred an office or being remote. Personally, I love an office. I love being around coworkers, grabbing lunch and getting out of my apartment. Im a homebody, and so its typical of me to stay in once Im in. Going to an office gets me out. But when asked I have no preference. I can work remote, I can work in an office. Im not picky. I live in a great area where I have a few coffee shops and a cool brewery that I can work from if Im working from home. I have a spare room in my apartment that is an office/bike room. </p>
<p>The same can be said about frameworks. I got asked about my preference for Laravel or Symfony. I don't care. I've used both, I like both. I can write code with both. My personal preference is Laravel only because at this point I have a few BASH scripts that spin up projects with packages I like easily. When it comes to a job I can't be bothered to care. I keep up with all the major frameworks, I watch their twitter accounts to see what is coming out. You can have a personal favorite, and still get a job by having strong opinions that are loosely held. Who knows, maybe as a Laravel developer you will look at Symfony and have new ideas. </p>
<p>The point being: the more picky you are in all of this, the more limiting you are. It's up to you to define how picky you want to be, but that pickiness comes with limits. Mainly, how long can you last on your money after the last paycheck comes in.</p>
<h3>Step Three - Take your time at first (I didn't)</h3>
<p>The byproduct of that tweet above is the amount of people reaching out offering me some time to talk about their teams, and why I should consider it. It worked out really well because I had a lot of people vouch for me which helped me out. In retrospect though, I should have taken the rest of the week to relax. I have money stored away, I was going be ok for a few days. Instead, I decided to hit it hard on Wednesday with 6 interviews I think. I did another 6 or so on Thursday too. By the end of Thursday I was <em>tired</em>. Talking to people physically hurt me. I went to a conference the next day, which was more effort but a different kind. I made it clear to companies that yea Im interviewing now, but Im not in a rush to find something. Im making sure I get the best amount of coverage and getting the best possible options for my next step. Im fortunate the place I landed doesnt have me starting til the end of the month so I have two weeks to work out, cycle, and do OSS.</p>
<p>What happened though, is that I came into the next week of funemployement with options. Really, it's a double edged sword. Move at your own speed and pace. I have seen developers, some really good developers, linger in unemployement for so long, that it kind of scared me and made me want to get things moving. Its a little bit of a confidence booster to see so many places work to line up interviews with you. However I burned myself out to the point where I ended up telling one company that. I was already getting offers when I had a request for a video chat so they could get an offer. I was so tired and out of it that I basically declined and told them Im so burned out that I couldn't talk. Since I had offers, I was ok doing it, but Im sure had I paced myself a bit more I could have heard more and had even more to consider. </p>
<p>Tip three: <strong>if time permits, take a few days to recenter yourself.</strong></p>
<h3>Step Four - It's not all about the money</h3>
<p>The last piece of advice I want to give is that while money is great and lets me live a lavish lifestyle of the rich and hipsterish, it's not everything. The spread of salaries I had in my offers was about $35k, not including benefits, options, and more. When I told one person I took the lowest paying one they were kind of taken back. They brought up how fast the highest salary gets to my main goal: early retirement. And they are absolutely right. However, as I see it with a lot of FIRE devotees: getting to FIRE quickly without a meaningful life built up, or arriving stressed and burned out is not worht it <em>at all</em>. I am aiming to retire in my 40's. I love what I do, but I would prefer to do exactly what I want to do: OSS and not have to worry about deadlines, stand ups or anything else. During the time I do have to work though I want to make sure I am at a company that values me, and wants me to take care of myself mentally and physically. Being prone to burn out, this was huge to hear from a company that they track PTO in order to make sure people take time off. They have a gym reimbursement program as well. Trading a large salary for a gym membership may seem silly, but what is the point of retiring early and being in terrible shape, miserable and depressed because I was overworking myself and not taking care of what needs to be tended too. This isn't to say I would be overworked in the other jobs, but taking care of myself is a big thing and this was a huge selling point to me. This is a decision only you can make. Take the highest salary if you want, take the lowest, but do what is best for you. To me though, money isn't everything and I prefer to see how a job will let me be my best self. That can't be measured in dollars in any way at all. </p>
<p>Tip four: <strong>money doesnt mean everything, sometimes the culture is worth its weight in gold.</strong></p>
<h3>Step Five - Stay Humble</h3>
<p>One thing I did after every interview I acquired via my tweet was thank them profusely for taking the time to talk to me. They were under no obligation to talk to me, so I wanted to make sure they time was well spent and they felt appreciated. I tried to thank every single person who quote tweeted my original tweet with kind words to make sure they knew they were appreciated in this hard time. When I turned down offers, I tried my hardest to start with just how grateful I was they would even consider offering me a job. It takes just a few seconds, but it goes a long, long way. So long that a few of the jobs I turned down told me if things don't work out I have a spot on their team. They don't have to do that, they will find other great developers, but because I did my best to stay humble and be appreciative, I have created lasting impressions and relationships now. </p>
<p>Tip five: <strong>stay humble, and thank everyone</strong>.</p>
<h3>Finale</h3>
<p>I think these five tips will help anyone. Whether you are just starting out ohave r been a developer for a while, taking care of your community connections, taking time for yourself and weighing your options will get you the best result. </p>
<p>I can't tell you how much I struggled and agonized over the decision of what team to join. It's a position that is incredibly hard. It took a lot of thought, a lot of personal intraspection and a lot of pros/cons lists. I had my dream job offered to me, more money than I've ever made, and opportunities to create amazing things. In the end Im confident I made the right decision for myself and I look forward to what it brings. </p>
<p>Have questions? Feel free to message me here or on twitter!</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/staying-motivated</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/staying-motivated" />
    <title>Staying Motivated</title>
    <published>2019-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">I was on the phone with my good friend Korvin Szanto yesterday when he asked how I keep motivated on days when I don&#039;t feel like riding or going to the gym. It sparked an interest to write a few thoughts down for anyone else who wonders how to keep......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>I was on the phone with my good friend <a href="https://twitter.com/korvinszanto">Korvin Szanto</a> yesterday when he asked how I keep motivated on days when I don't feel like riding or going to the gym. It sparked an interest to write a few thoughts down for anyone else who wonders how to keep going. </p>
<h3>The fight to keep going</h3>
<p>This year started off differently for me, and so far it has continued to be different. I woke up 2019 determined to make some changes. The past few years have been a mix of apathy, lethergy, anger, and no motivation to change myself. For whatever reason, I didn't want 2019 to be the same thing. I started reading all kinds of books, figured out how to make running suck less to get to cycling season, and started lifting. Now, I've started tracking what I eat, making better choices for food, and trying to make sure I stay away from soda and things like that. Even beer has been cut down drastically. </p>
<p>The thing is though is that this isn't easy. It's hard to keep going every single day. Even rest days require more thought and planning. So how do you keep it up day and day out?</p>
<h3>You only get one body. Treat it like a temple.</h3>
<p>Im not to this stage yet, but this is a paraphrased quote from Terry Crews. If you don't know him, he spends hours in the gym every single day. He is also really funny. In one interview he was asked why he spends so much time in the gym. The headline above summarises it pretty well. We don't know what happens when we die, but we do know our bodies don't go with us. But in order to get further in life, you need to take care of your body while you have it. And what motivates me to keep working on it? Well a few things. </p>
<ul>
<li>Airplane seats are uncomfortable if you are fat. </li>
<li>Going outside in the summer and immediately sweating</li>
<li>Running out of breath just taking the stairs</li>
<li>Clothes looking bad. </li>
</ul>
<p>As someone who has done a lot of traveling this year for conferences, I can tell you first hand being squished in an airplane seat is enough on its own. Last night (July 8th, 2019), I went out to an art crawl downtown. It was so much fun. But when I was done, I looked at my shirt and it was covered in sweat. No one wants to see that. It's not a good look. When it comes time to a work out (I prefer cycling), I know that its just an hour of work but it will give me days of fulfillment. There are days I don't want to go, but I put on my shoes and gym shorts, walk over there and even if I just do 20 minutes on the elliptical, that counts to me as effort towards the goal. Same thing with a walk with my dog. A 30 minute walk is good enough to count, and thankfully podcasts and Audible help me make it even better. </p>
<h3>Little improvements over big improvements</h3>
<p>One book I read detailed the rise of the Team Sky (now Team Ineos) cycling team. The manager, Sir Dave Brailsford, realized something simple: a 1% improvement daily beats a massive improvement once a week. With that, he went to the riders of the team, and started making micro adjustments to how they rode, how their bikes were set up, what they wore. And it paid off. The team became a dominant force in European cycling winning the Tour De France multiple times, along with other major rides. When I heard this, this is what I knew I needed to do. I didn't hit 265 pounds over night, and I wasn't going to hit 200 pounds over night either. 1% improvements were the goal. When I check my weight, seeing the scale move down just .1 pound is enough for a victory. Being able to ride a well ridden route .10 mph faster is a win. Micro improvements seem to be the winner in how I stay motivated. I know over time, these 1% improvements will total up to 10% improvement in speed or a 15% improvement in weight lifted or 20% reduction in sweat. </p>
<p>If you think you can start going to the gym today and by the end of the week deadlift 200 pounds, you are wrong and will lose motivation when you don't hit that goal. Instead, going to the gym now, laying the foundation and improving just ever so much will help you reach that goal of 200 pound deadlifts. How do I get there? I start by doing a set to failure with deadlifting, finding out my limit. Then once I do, every lift after that is just a small amount more. Will I deadlift 200 in a week? No. But I will in a month. In fact I will probably blow through it. </p>
<h3>The sense of worth gains</h3>
<p>The last thing that keeps me motivated to do all of this is how much my self esteem has risen and how much everything else has decreased. Instead of wallowing in stress, I grab my bike and let a hill take it out of me. When I put on a shirt, instead of it being tight, its now loose. Thats a huge win. And because of that, I feel better. Im not there yet, but I will get there. And hopefully some of this will help you stay motivated as well.</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/improving</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/improving" />
    <title>On Improving</title>
    <published>2019-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">A funny thing happened today. I was riding in an organized cycling ride called the Georgia 400 Century, named from a popular highway that takes people from the suburbs of Atlanta to downtown. The catch for this ride is that
you spend about 3 miles on the......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>A funny thing happened today. I was riding in an organized cycling ride called the Georgia 400 Century, named from a popular highway that takes people from the suburbs of Atlanta to downtown. The catch for this ride is that
you spend about 3 miles on the actual highway. Police close it off at 7am and we get 30 minutes to get on and back off. It's so much fun, and I look forward to this ride now every year since I did it three years ago. The idea behind this post is what my mother said to me. </p>
<h3>You must be tired</h3>
<p>Every year I've done this ride, my parents like to meet me at the rest stops and see how it goes. This year, my father rode with me (he did the 9 mile course), and we rode together up til the on ramp to the highway when I broke ahead and caught up to a group averaging my pace. My mom was waiting at the top of the dreaded Mother in Law hill (there is 3 massive hills called the Three Sisters, and once last one called the Mother in Law. We end on that, so its a great punch in the face) when I saw her about 42 minutes in. She waited for my dad, collected him and they came home so he could shower. After that they tried to connect with me at a rest stop. Except I kept blowing through them. Even with stopping, refilling bottles, eating gu (not as strange as it sounds), and resting for a minute, I was on the last pit stop when they got to the third one. When I finished, my mom initially thought I was just tired and confused until she say the times I posted on Strava and realized I've gotten incredibly more powerful and faster in the past year. This is how I did it, and how it can be related not just to cycling but pretty much anything.</p>
<h3>It's good to fail</h3>
<p>In cycling, failure is mostly centered around getting dropped from the group. What that means is instead of slowing down, they are leaving you behind. If you are going on this ride, its expected that you know that, know the route, and will eventually finish. Originally when I started riding with groups, I did a no drop ride. It was fun, but also not terribly challenging, so when a new group at a sister shop popped up I made the move. I went from riding with commuters and people who ride causually to racers and people averaging north of 100 miles a week. Suffice to say, it was a challenge. After being dropped, I started working out and working hard on non-group days to catch up. It eventually worked that I would be able to hang longer. I did cheat a little and bought a Garmin that gives me data about my speed, cadence, time etc so that way I could climb hills easier (it's still not easy). But in less than a year, I went from being dropped and kind of dreading the ride to showing up ready to go. Getting dropped isn't terrible, its a good reminder that I have work to do. </p>
<h3>Find people smarter and better than you</h3>
<p>In order to get to the level I needed to be, I found people who are faster, stronger, and better than me. I push myself to keep up, they don't drop themselves down. This can be applied to pretty much anything. When I was learning how to program, I followed all kinds of people on twitter I knew to be more experienced and smarter than I. It was a great way to ramp up and learn. Was it easy to keep up? Not at all, but when I look back, I'm thankful for how it worked out. I'm doing the same with photography. I look at people who have been doing it for years, understanding their lens choices and their choice of composition. Am I going to go out and do the same thing right now? No, not yet. However, watching them helps me remain mindful to what I am doing before I press the action button on my camera.</p>
<p>You can't get better without failing. You will always find a way to fail. Whether you are dropped from a ride, fired from a job, not selling photos, giving a bad conference talk or anything else, the thought of failure looms large and is ready to make itself known. Instead of fearing it, accept it, love it, and use it to move yourself forward. Eventually you will see improvement and even wow the people watching you.</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/reimaging-life</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/reimaging-life" />
    <title>Reinventing Life</title>
    <published>2019-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">A few weeks, I took to twitter to put my phone number and email up and blocked the site from my browsers. I don&#039;t know how long it will last, but I know one thing: I&#039;m happier. Who knew at 32 I would be trying to transform all aspects of my life. 

The......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>A few weeks, I took to twitter to put my phone number and email up and blocked the site from my browsers. I don't know how long it will last, but I know one thing: I'm happier. Who knew at 32 I would be trying to transform all aspects of my life. </p>
<h3>Speaking</h3>
<p>The coolest thing first: I'm speaking at Cascadia PHP this September up in Portland and I am so excited. I went there last year and had an absolute blast. The team up there did an amazing job organizing a conference. My talk is going to cover the community and moreso why its such an amazing resource so many of us have at our disposal. I will tease parts of it as I write it. If you are going to be up there, let me know. My current plan is to spend a few days up there longer than the conference working from our office there and exploring the city. </p>
<p>I will also be speaking at a rad little JS conference here in Nashville called UndergroundJS. If you are in Nashville, I highly suggest getting a ticket. My talk here is a keynote and a topic I am passionate about: Mental Health. Any chance to help out the local communities is a huge win in my book. </p>
<h3>Photography</h3>
<p>I'm diving deeper into this hobby, and actively pursuring opportunities to both grow and make a little money with it. Turns out camera lenses are expensive. The one I am jonesing for is that beautiful Canon 70-200mm f/2.8 I had in Miami at Sunshine and Austin at Longhorn. It's such a great lens and I had fun with it. I can't thank Josh Holmes enough for trusting me to let me use it for days on end. It really inspired me to do some awesome things. </p>
<p>Today I picked up a new lens, the Sigma 17-50mm that I saw in a YouTube video from a guy who does a lot of Disney Photography and I can tell I am going to love this lens. What I love most is how photography gets me out of my usual view of the world and makes me think about new angles and new perspectives. It's a way to create while yet not being on a computer. That bit has become a recurring theme. </p>
<h3>Cycling</h3>
<p>Most people know my love for the bike. Road bikes, city bikes, e-bikes, or any other bike is cool with me. Im closing in on 1000 miles ridden on the year. A goal that seemed elusive in the past is now something I will crush by the end of the month. Part of it is due to rearranging priorities, but it also comes down to being inspired by Cody and our boss. They are both running more and more each day. While I think running is the worst, cycling is my go to, but I can transform their running plans to cycling plans and go with it. </p>
<p>What is even cooler is the ride I do at the end of June in Atlanta will have a special guest: my father. My father has never been overly athletic, nor interested in doing it. He will come support me but thats it. This year, he has made some incredible changes as well, and I look forward to doing the first 9 miles with him and watching him cross the line while I continue on.</p>
<h3>Away from the computer</h3>
<p>When I woke up on January 1st, 2019 I had a few goals written out. I've never been one for New Year's Resolutions or anything. Mostly because I never complete them. This year started out the same but then my boss sparked my passion for reading with a few great audiobook recs. It was a gateway drug that hasn't stopped. Combined with dead tree versions, I've ran through some books ranging from personal finance to overcoming anxiety and fear to digital minimalism. The last one has really got me working on not being at a computer at all hours of the day, and instead being outside and being actively involved in life. I can safely say my life has changed for the better. This week I have gotten up around 5:40 in the morning and ride with the sunrise. I used to toss and turn, fighting with my phone and the desire to sleep more. Now I just grab my bike. Its spurred some weight loss too, and Im about to be on the good side of 250. I can't remember the last time I was under 250. </p>
<p>Pulling away from Twitter helped me strengthen friendships too. To the ones who have reached out, Im incredibly grateful for you. You are what makes my life so awesome. Kat Zien, bless her heart, loves to text me at 4am pictures of Bingo, the Monzo office dog. I dont know if she knows, but it always makes me wake up with a smile. Nic Rosental, a friend from Atlanta, and I have found a mutual interest in photography and we nerd out on lenses, pictures, and things like that. There are others, from Ben Edmunds, one of the coolest people out there, Mike Bifulco who loves bikes, and people not in the tech community. </p>
<p>I can't urge people enough to get off twitter/facebook/whatever and get out to experience life in a different way. Im way more mellow than I was before. My anxiety has dropped and instead of wondering what will go wrong, I wonder what can make the current situation <em>better</em>. I'll still be around. I have projects to work on (PHPVersions, Fractal), talks to right and things to blog about. But Im probably gonna mix more non-tech topics in with this. It will be better once I figure out the tag system here. When I get enough content to move the photography or bikes to its own blog I will, but for now, you get all of me. </p>
<p>Cheers!</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/invest-in-yourself</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/invest-in-yourself" />
    <title>Invest in yourself.</title>
    <published>2019-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">For the past 6 years or so I&#039;ve been doing everything I can to learn software development. It started when I realized it was a career option and it hasn&#039;t stopped. Along the way I sold my Xbox, stopped playing guitar, and put all of my efforts into what......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>For the past 6 years or so I've been doing everything I can to learn software development. It started when I realized it was a career option and it hasn't stopped. Along the way I sold my Xbox, stopped playing guitar, and put all of my efforts into what I am doing today. On the one hand, it seems to have worked out well as I am now a senior software engineer. On the other though, I turned 30 a few years ago and realized my hobbies were all programming related. As I turn 32 in a few weeks (let's not talk about it), I started making some changes to make sure my life was as rich as possible. I don't mean rich in the financial sense (although that is part of it) but I mean in the sense of having amazing experiences. </p>
<h3>You can't take it with you when you die.</h3>
<p>I have been fairly open about my financial struggles and efforts over the years. While this post isn't about that, one thing I have started doing is trying to be more generous with the money I have. As the saying goes &quot;you can't take it with you when you die&quot; and so I would rather help people now. I've given myself a goal that at least twice a month I need to find some sort of cause to donate to. Whether it's a friend from high school raising money for their honors college program or a coworker's kid raising money for their wrestling team, they are all worthy causes in those people's eyes. I challenge you to do the same. Money can't buy happiness, but it can help create lasting memories. </p>
<h3>Lifelong learning.</h3>
<p>The internet is full of amazing ways to learn something new. I should know: the interet is how I learned to program. I don't know where I would be without it. While it's great to have some fun to troll, there is a vast amount of ways to learn something new. One thing I started was to watch a TED Talk a day. Or at least I try. TED Talks, and I try to find the official ones before the TEDx ones, are a great source for learning. The people presenting are passionate about the topic they are talking about, and usually its about something I have no idea about. Based on when you are reading this (if anyone reads this), the current fascination is that we finally have a picture of a black hole. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjj_vXvzsrhAhUphOAKHXkoD3MQyCkwAHoECAoQBA&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ted.com%2Ftalks%2Fkatie_bouman_what_does_a_black_hole_look_like%3Flanguage%3Den&amp;usg=AOvVaw3zU3re3jvsmEdCZ8ZaZRUy">Katie Bouman</a>, a lead scientist and developer on the project, gave a TED talk about what the process was to get this image. Her excitement was contagious and you can tell from the video that she is bursting with energy wanting to show everyone how cool this is. I've watched this video twice and I am still learning things from her talk. I challenge you to watch a TED talk, or something similar, once a week or so and think on it. </p>
<h3>Hobbies</h3>
<p>The last thing I have made a push on is getting better hobbies. Not to long ago I would sit on the weekends coding my life away. That's not a good way to live! Thanks to friends like Jacques Woodcock, Kat Zien, Michael Moussa, Cody Covey, Rob Allen and Kevin Boyd, I have a great group of people for two of my favorite hobbies: cycling and photography. Between riding 45 miles in Miami to getting photography help, these people have all helped me develop these hobbies to something that brings me joy. Now on the weekends I give bike tours, venture downtown (what a nightmare) with my camera, ride out to a remote area and see new areas. The camera gives me a new way to see the world. Whether its a tight image of a flower, or a sweeping landscape of a city skyline, you find new ways to view old things. With biking, you get to explore a city from a different angle. You are more alert to people walking and cars driving, but also to intersections, bridges and other areas of interest. You can easily park your bike on top of a bridge for a quick picture and you can then keep going with the wind in your face! What hobbies do you have that get you away from the computer?</p>
<h3>Reading</h3>
<p>The last thing I have done, thnaks to my boss, is found my love of reading. A huge help has bene Audible, which I tend to listen to on the drive to and from work and while out walking my dog. While I still love a physical book, the audio books help so much. From personal finance to fiction to personal growth, the amount you can get into is just amazing. This year I have finished more books than in the past 5 years. I have finished two personal finance books, a book about leadership, a book about the 96 Everest disaster, and am now reading a book about principles from Ray Dalio. If it's a physical book I try to set aside 30 minutes a day, usually at the end, to read. I have a nice comfy chair to curl up in and just let myself get lost. It helps me think, be creative, and sleep. </p>
<p>All of these are things Im doing to invest more in myself and enrich my life. I challenge you to do the same. Whether its woodworking, reading, or exploring you can create an enriched life by creating experiences that can't be forgotten and will stay with you forever. </p>
<p>Cheers!</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/playing-with-fire</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/playing-with-fire" />
    <title>Playing With Fire</title>
    <published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">The image I chose for this post serves as a reminder for what awaits when I hit my goals. It&#039;s an image from Holi, a celebration of light in India that takes place in March. The celebration recognizes the emergence of spring and the end of winter. One of......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>The image I chose for this post serves as a reminder for what awaits when I hit my goals. It's an image from Holi, a celebration of light in India that takes place in March. The celebration recognizes the emergence of spring and the end of winter. One of my goals is to make it over there for the celebration. I'm not a religious person but this celebration just fascinates me. If you want to see more, there is a Netflix series called &quot;Tales by Light&quot; that follows photographers around. One episode follows a photographer as he wades through the crowds of Holi and it's amazing. </p>
<p>I bring this up because a few weeks ago I finished the book <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Playing-Financial-Independence-Retire-Early-ebook/dp/B07JVC5F7N/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=playing+with+fire&amp;qid=1553350721&amp;s=gateway&amp;sr=8-1">&quot;Playing With Fire&quot;</a> by Scott Rieckens. It follows Scott, his wife and daughter on a journey from living paycheck to paycheck in high power careers to reworking everything to live on less than half of what they usually spend a month and being financially independent. Its a quick read, the chapters are short but entrancing. I bought it right before my flight up to Minneapolis for Midwest PHP and I had it finished on the flight back to Nashville days later. If I wasn't socializing or working on my talks, I was reading this book. </p>
<p>To give you an idea of how the story goes: Scott and his wife went from driving a new car year after year, having a yacht club membership, going to dinner with friends at expensive restaurants every week to finding a used but efficient car, giving up the membership and entertaining friends at home with wine and home cooked meals. The story follows their decision making and does a great job grappling with what a lot of people struggle with: how much is too much to slash away. With the Financial Independence/Retire Early community there are various levels of frugality and morality. Some people take it to the extreme, giving up just about everything deemed excessive while others weigh what matters most for them. What Scott figures out early on is the things that bring them the most happiness aren't material things but experiences. I did an exercise last week to determine what really brings me happiness. Things on my list were:</p>
<ul>
<li>Cycling</li>
<li>Photography</li>
<li>Working Out </li>
<li>Music </li>
<li>Exploring new areas</li>
</ul>
<p>Now, there are start up costs involved, but after that Im good to go. For photography you don't need the most amazing camera and lens, you just need an eye for composition. For cycling, a carbon frame will be super light weight and awesome, but unless you are about to ride in the Tour De France and climb the Pyrenees, you don't really need it. You can get by with a used hybrid and just ride. </p>
<p>What I liked most about the book though is Scott didn't hide his struggles with their journey. There were times the family came close to calling it and as the cliche goes, found a spark that renewed their drive. Might it be getting connected with people who have already made the journey like Brandon from <a href="https://www.madfientist.com/">MadFientist</a>, Pete from <a href="https://mrmoneymustache.com">Mr. Money Mustache</a>, or <a href="https://jlcollinsnh.com/about/">JL Collins</a> who wrote one of my favorite books &quot;The Simple Path to Wealth&quot;. The book is honest and refreshing from the typical FIRE blogs where people slash and burn everythig for a singular goal. They talk about giving and taking in the journey. Early on, Scott's wife Taylor was hesitant but opened up and started to get on board with one caveat: she would not give up nice chocolate and wine. Super relatable to everyone. As I push on with my journey to getting to financial indepedence, I look around and realize that good coffee and good whiskey are two things I want to enjoy. I'm fine giving up other things, but coffee and whiskey are two things that I want to enjoy the finer parts of. </p>
<p>I highly recommend this book, its a great look at a tough journey written with a lot of humility and honesty. Pick it up today and you will have it finished by Monday. If you do, let me know your thoughts!</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/phpversions</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/phpversions" />
    <title>The New PhpVersions</title>
    <published>2019-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">About 2 ish years or so ago, I got access to the PhpVersions.info project started by my good friend
Phil Sturgeon. There was always an open issue for a rewrite of the project. The reason being that the project was started in Jekyll to take advantage of......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>About 2 ish years or so ago, I got access to the <a href="http://phpversions.info">PhpVersions.info</a> project started by my good friend
<a href="https://twitter.com/philsturgeon">Phil Sturgeon</a>. There was always an open issue for a rewrite of the project. The reason being that the project was started in Jekyll to take advantage of Github's free hosting. That worked <em>great</em> for a few years, but it became obvious we should use PHP since the whole project was about getting people on to the latest and greatest PHP version. </p>
<p>I started to examine options out there, and there are some great options out there. Ultimately, I chose Laravel with Vue.Js, mainly because at the time that was the stack I was working full time in and knew I could get going with it fairly quickly. Say what you will about Laravel, and there is plenty to be said, one thing Laravel does great is &quot;Rapid Application Development&quot;, in which you can get up and running in no time. It's pretty fantastic. Now, if you can at least plan for a little bit in the future,you can also future proof your application from growing stale with a framework. With that, I set out to write the project. </p>
<p>It wasn't til I was sitting at WordCamp Kent when I seriously put in the time to do it. I was speaking at the conference and the talks weren't really relevant to me so I just hung out working on it. I got the bulk down and then it was time to come back to reality. The project was worked on in between organizing a conference, speaking and other things. Finally, <a href="https://twitter.com/colinodell">Colin O'Dell</a> stepped up to helo manage the v1 instance pull requests so I could dedicate my time to the new stuff. </p>
<h3>Tech Stack</h3>
<p>As I mentioned above, the back end portion of the project is currently powered by Laravel. Will that remain the same as time passes I do not know. I'd like to think I wrote it in a way where we can start to remove the underlaying Laravel code after a while and move to packages. On the other hand, Laravel clearly is not going anywhere. I am not terribly concerned one way or another. The database is just MySQL. Woo. One of these days I need to get back to Postgres. </p>
<p>The front end is powered by Vue.js, a reactive front end framework started back in 2014. Its comparable to React, but has some really nice differences. I did a talk about Vue.js at Sunshine which was fun. The CSS framework is Tailwind CSS, which I have absolutely enjoyed using, the font is Questrial and the icon font is Zondicons.</p>
<p>It all runs on a Digital Ocean droplet with PHP 7.3 installed, and I absolutely plan on moving to 7.4 as soon as it is avaiable. </p>
<p>If you have questions, ideas or want to contribute check out the <a href="https://github.com/phpversions/phpversions.info">repository</a>.</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/the-case-against-hateoas</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/the-case-against-hateoas" />
    <title>The Case Against HATEOAS</title>
    <published>2019-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">One thing I love about API Design is talking about HATEOAS. HATEOAS is magical, and generally considered the hardest part of API Design. I wonder why that could be though? Could it be that dynamically creating a link to a resource is that hard? No, I......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>One thing I love about API Design is talking about HATEOAS. HATEOAS is magical, and generally considered the hardest part of API Design. I wonder why that could be though? Could it be that dynamically creating a link to a resource is that hard? No, I don't think so. Could it be that Hypermedia isn't taught? Perhaps. More importantly: HATEOAS is a daunting term. Breaking it down HATEOAS becomes &quot;Hypermedia As The Engine Of Application State&quot;. Let's let that sink in just a bit. </p>
<p>I am going to suggest something here: let's stop using HATEOAS and instead just use <code>links</code> or <code>hypermedia</code>. Breaking this whole thing
down to the simpliest term will help developers down the road.</p>
<p>I remember a year ago I went to the Nashville Software School to talk about what it's like to be a developer in the wild.
I did a free form AMA and one question was, and I paraphrase, &quot;how do you remember all the acronyms that are associated to development?&quot;. I paused for a bit
and gave some answer along the lines of &quot;you just kind of remember them as you go&quot;. As I look back, that answer is garbage. It is in a similar vein
of playing guitar where you eventually remember the different chord positions. What is different though is that you wont always use the
acronyms in daily use. HATEOAS is absolutely one of them. The worst part is that HATEOAS is not at all part of everyone's job like DI, CI, HTTP and others.</p>
<p>At it's core, what exactly is HATEOAS? Well, to understand HATEOAS, you need to understand REST. REST, or Representational State Transfer is the idea of stateless
data transfer either between a machine and human or machine to machine. By design, your REST API should remain stateless, and not remember what the previous request was.
This poses a problem though: if our API doesn't remember the last request made, how can we tell a user what other endpoints they may be interested in? This is where hypermedia, or links, come into play.
A great example of this is the Foxy.io API, borrowed from <a href="https://api.foxycart.com/docs">here</a>:</p>
<pre><code class="language-json">{
    "_links": {
        ...
        "fx:customers": {
            "href": "https://api.foxycart.com/stores/41000/customers",
            "title": "Customers for This Store"
        },
        "fx:transactions": {
            "href": "https://api.foxycart.com/stores/41000/transactions",
            "title": "Transactions for This Store"
        },
        "fx:subscriptions": {
            "href": "https://api.foxycart.com/stores/41000/subscriptions",
            "title": "Subscriptions for This Store"
        },
        ...
    },
    ...
}</code></pre>
<p>What we get here is part of the response payload, where the Foxy.io developers point out that while you are looking at the current data, here are some links of interest that you may want to utilize. Looking at what is available, the main response is for some sort of store endpoint, and now we can see that we may be interested in the store's customers, transactions or subscriptions as well. This is HATEOAS. If we
request the <code>/store</code> endpoint again, the same links will be present, but the service we requested data from will not remember what we did. This is ideal. </p>
<h3>The Case Against HATEOAS</h3>
<p>Now, after reading all of that, you are probably thinking &quot;ya that makes sense&quot;, which is great. However now Im going to make it a point to stop using HATEOAS. Why? Because people dont know it off hand like
CI, DI, HTTP, and other things. Instead, lets just call it <code>links</code> or <code>hypermedia</code>, and remove a barrier to learning something that we consider crucial to API Design. </p>
<p>If we can make it easier for one person, we make APIs better for a lot of people.</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/new-year-new-me</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/new-year-new-me" />
    <title>New Year, New Me</title>
    <published>2019-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">What can you challenge yourself with to be the best you? Here are mine.

In my &amp;quot;year in review&amp;quot; post I mentioned I got into photography. For 2019 one thing I want to do is take a picture a day. There are a few things I hope to achieve with......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>What can you challenge yourself with to be the best you? Here are mine.</p>
<h3>A photograph a day.</h3>
<p>In my &quot;year in review&quot; post I mentioned I got into photography. For 2019 one thing I want to do is take a picture a day. There are a few things I hope to achieve with this:</p>
<ol>
<li>I hope to get better at composition and framing. </li>
<li>I hope it challenges me to explore more. </li>
<li>Give me a portfolio of stuff to hopefully sell/create monetary options.</li>
</ol>
<p>To follow along, check out my <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/164111164@N05/">flickr</a>. I hope to move all the content to my own site soon. Just gotta buid it.</p>
<h3>Read 52 Books</h3>
<p>I used to be a huge reader. I would crush a series of books in no time as a kid. I have sadly fallen off in recent years, so I hope to pick that back up. The first three books of the new year are: </p>
<ol>
<li>Jurassic Park (holy shit so good)</li>
<li>Into The Wild</li>
<li>Simple Path to Wealth</li>
</ol>
<p>There is no real method to the madness here. I picked up Jurassic Park cause it caught my eye. As for Into The Wild, I loved Jon Krakauer's recount of the 1996 Everest Diaster in Into Thin Air, so I hope
this will be a good read. Simple Path To Wealth is a book I've heard references on countless FI/RE podcasts and interviews. I love JL Collin's style of discussion. Even keeled, soft spoken but authoritative
in the realm of wealth and investment, I think this will be a game changer. </p>
<p>To follow along, check out my <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/4986797-matt-trask">goodreads</a></p>
<h3>Two new blogs</h3>
<p>As I referenced above, I want to move my photographs to my own content management system for a few reasons. Mainly I want to control how it is shown,
and should something happen to flickr, I don't want to scramble to get my images. </p>
<p>The other blog will be a personal finance blog aimed at developers. I've tweeted about it a few times and the response is always &quot;yes please&quot;. As I read a lot of 2018 review blog posts, one thing mentioned
was getting the finances in order but very few people know where to start. I hope the aim of my blog will be a mix of good foundational starting points as well as more advanced
topics like FI/RE, investing, real estate and more. </p>
<p>Look for these, I will be tweeting and posting about them as they get close to be done.</p>
<h3>Walk more</h3>
<p>I live in a great area of Nashville. There is a coffee shop .5 miles away, a brewery .3 miles away and an excellent sandwich shop .5 miles away in the opposite direction. There is no reason
for me to drive other than I want to waste resources. So a challenge of mine is to walk more, be more in the community I am apart of and enjoy it. A side effect is hopefully some weight loss. </p>
<h3>Weight loss</h3>
<p>I've struggled for years to lose weight, or rather be motivated to lose weight. I am not getting younger, but I have plenty of time to enjoy life and feel better. I am to do this through better eating,
less garbage like soda, more walking, more cycling, and maybe running. Maybe.</p>
<h3>Remove the last of my debts</h3>
<p>I have two loans right now. A student loan at $6,000-ish dollars and a personal loan for $8,000-ish dollars. These suck! It's a weight just hanging over you. I want them gone, so they will be.
I've spent the morning running numbers and preparing myself for a financially healthy 2019. These should pave the way for my net worth to grow, and free up money to pump into stocks like VTSAX. </p>
<p>I aim to talk more in depth about all this on the financial blog I mentioned earlier. </p>
<h3>Loose ends</h3>
<p>I think this covers it. I am working on being happier, more confident and more at peace with life. 2018 was a struggle at times for various reasons. I gained weight, destroyed some relationships (dating and not dating),
and basically was just down on myself the whole time. I am a good developer (sometimes), and I have things to offer but I can't offer them if I am not at my best. </p>
<p>So 2019, come at me. It'll be fun.</p>
<p>See ya!</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/year-in-review</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/year-in-review" />
    <title>Year in Review</title>
    <published>2018-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">It&#039;s always good to do a year in review, and this year was a big year for me, so this will be a big post.

The biggest change for me came in January when I was offered a position at OpenSky, now MoreCommerce to work under Wage. It was a big change, going......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>It's always good to do a year in review, and this year was a big year for me, so this will be a big post.</p>
<h2>Work</h2>
<p>The biggest change for me came in January when I was offered a position at OpenSky, now MoreCommerce to work under <a href="https://twitter.com/jwage">Wage</a>. It was a big change, going from a small team all cramped in a room to a distributed team across the world. I won't say its been easy either. It is a huge application across a lot of repositories. But, because the team practices good programming concepts, its not hard to figure out where you are in the app. It's because of those practices the app which I think is well over 7 years old is still in great shape. </p>
<p>I've had the opportunity to really work on some cool stuff, but it has been a huge challenge. It's made me think about how I code and work altogether. While its been a lot of ups, there was also a good bit of time where my anxiety was at an all time high. Not just cause of work, but it had an effect on it. It showed me I work with people who care and want to see everyone in good health and spirits. Im happy I made the switch, even if there were times I was borderline thinking I wasnt at my best there. </p>
<h2>Community</h2>
<p>On the community side, it was a roller coaster of fun and frolics. I started the year as an organizer of Nashville PHP and am ending it as an organizer of NashAPIs. In the middle I stepped down from Nashville PHP to run Southeast PHP. There is a subsequent blog post about Southeast PHP around here somewhere, but suffice to say it was a success. Four years ago, I never imagined I would run a conference but drunk me does silly things like commit to running a conferece. Drunk me is an asshole.</p>
<p>On top of organizing a conference, I had the pleasure to attend Sunshine PHP and had the honor to speak at the inaugural Cascadia PHP about the OpenAPI Spec. While I was there, I got to meet coworkers who work in our Portland office.</p>
<p>Locally, I helped get NashAPIs off the ground. It's still a work in progress, but it's coming along.</p>
<h2>Open Source</h2>
<p>My biggest achievement here is not letting PHPVersions.info fall to the wayside. I've tried my best to stay up with the pull requests, but the biggest help has definitely come from <a href="https://twitter.com/colinodell">Colin O'Dell</a>. He is on top of the things I forget about. This also is a good way to segue into one of my goals:</p>
<ul>
<li>Getting PHPVersions off Jekyll/Github and on to well PHP. </li>
</ul>
<p>The project is all about highlighting PHP hosts offering the latest PHP Versions, so we should absolutely be up with that for our own code base. I can tell you right now, the project 75% done, with it mostly being small things I need to fix. I just need like a 4 day stretch of time where I can work on it and get it done. It would be awesome to finish it before Sunshine PHP so I can highlight it in my Vue.JS talk since Im using Vue.JS on the front end with Laravel on the backend. If you are familiar with the project and have ideas of what could be done to make it better, open an issue and tag me!</p>
<p>The other cool thing that happened with this project was I was interviewed. I didn't start the project, but Im happy to see it grow and people are taking notice. You can read the interview <a href="https://www.hostingadvice.com/blog/php-versions-tracks-language-updates-and-hosting-support/?fbclid=IwAR1qR8hymae6ndsGnlYCaJ6FGc5uI6vWMcdaandt6rqwCh6LdlQVOUaR1l0">here</a>.</p>
<p>Outside of this, I continue to look for opportunities to contribute more either through code or mentoring.</p>
<h2>Cycling</h2>
<p>My cycling goals dragged this year. According to my Strava profile, I rode 874 miles this year, down from last year. Not sure why exactly, just lost time with organizing things. Next year it's definitely something I want to pick up. I did do two major rides: </p>
<ul>
<li>Tour De Nash</li>
<li>GA 400 Century</li>
</ul>
<p>I did the 25 mile version of both, because I under trained. However, both were so much fun. I love the Tour de Nash cause it has enough competition to push you, but it's so friendly and welcoming. Whether you want to hammer out the lead or just casually ride through the various neighborhoods of Nashville, this ride has it all. </p>
<p>The GA 400 Century is a whole nother beast. This was the second year I did it, and what is special about it is that you get to ride on part of a freeway. Yes it's blocked off, and we only have 30 minutes to get on and off again. Its all of about a mile and a half on the freeway, and then it just kicks your ass with hills that seem to never end. Last year I did the 48 mile route and this year due to under training I dropped to the 25 mile route. Im sad I couldnt pull off the 48 again, but I still had so much fun. </p>
<p>I also had the pleasure to start giving bike tours. This is something I just lucked into but man its so much fun. I get to ride around Nashville talking about history, two things I love. Not Nashville, riding a bike and history. Nashville is... ok.
I get to make a bit of money on the side, and meet cool people so Im looking forward to the weather warmning up and getting back out there. </p>
<p>I have plans so far for three big rides: </p>
<ul>
<li>Tour De Nash - 48 Miles</li>
<li>GA 400 Century - 62 Miles</li>
<li>Sunrise Century - 62 Miles</li>
</ul>
<p>Doable, if I commit. </p>
<h2>Photography</h2>
<p>Another hobby I picked up is photography. I was fortunate enough to get a nice starter camera from a coworker and now it comes everywhere with me. In fact as I write this, Im picking up two more lenses. It's a fun hobby that lets me look at the world differently, and lets me explore. I just need to get a small point and shoot camera for when Im out riding, cause you never know what you will see on the long rides.</p>
<p>To see some of the photos I have taken, go <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/164111164@N05/">here</a>. If you see me around a conference, I will probably have my camera with me. </p>
<h2>2019</h2>
<p>Im planning on making 2019 my year. I was in a weird spot with 2018. I fought boughts of anxiety, depression and had a huge crisis of confidence for the latter part of the year. So bad my boss called me out on it all. And that helped. But now I need to make 2019 better. I want to take more risks, fail more, learn more, and be more. So my goals are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Lose weight</li>
<li>Take a picture a day</li>
<li>Read 52 books</li>
<li>Contribute more code</li>
<li>Explore</li>
</ul>
<p>The losing weight thing is already in effect (holiadys not withstanding). As I tweeted out a few days ago, I was able to get into a smaller pair of jeans. They are super tight, but its a nice victory none the less, and gives me the motivation to keep going. </p>
<p>As for the picture a day, I want to push myself to explore, look for new ways to see things, and create. Im hoping to stand up a blog soon to create a stream for the photos. Nothing fancy, just something to show a picture a day and maybe a caption. I think if I can get to the halfway mark, I will treat myself to a new camera as a way to reward dedication and effort. </p>
<p>I used to be a big reader. I would crush books as a kid. The whole Boxcar Children series in a month, Goosebumps in as much time. Harry Potter was a big one too. Being an adult has left me with less time to read so I want to change that. I went out and bought two books already to get me started. </p>
<p>The last two are just self explainitory. But I look forward to making them happen too. </p>
<p>Hopefully you had a great 2018 and you are ready to take on 2019!</p>
<p>Cheers!</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/conference-tips-and-tricks</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/conference-tips-and-tricks" />
    <title>Conference Tips and Tricks</title>
    <published>2018-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">So you get to go to a conference? That&#039;s awesome! Conferences have had a huge impact on my career. From attending to speaking (and keynoting) to organizing, I&#039;ve done it all. Along the way, I&#039;ve changed how I attend conferences and hope to give you some......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>So you get to go to a conference? That's awesome! Conferences have had a huge impact on my career. From attending to speaking (and keynoting) to organizing, I've done it all. Along the way, I've changed how I attend conferences and hope to give you some tips to take with you. </p>
<h3>Bring a water bottle.</h3>
<p>This was a game changer at <a href="https://twitter.com/midwestphp">Midwest PHP</a>. I don't know what prompted me to bring it, but I can say that I won't forget it in the future. Conferences have <em>alot</em> going on. And it's easy to forget the simple things like drinking water and staying hydrated. If you don't have something to reminder you, a bottle per se; it's not hard to go a great while without some water. More importantly, conferences tend to offer sodas/coffee/teas/booze so if you want to go the distance, having a near constant source of water helps. I love my liter Nalgene bottle, but get one that works for you.</p>
<h3>Don't be afraid to talk to speakers.</h3>
<p>I did a podcast a few weeks ago and the host admitted to me that he saw me at <a href="https://twitter.com/sunshinephp">Sunshine PHP</a> but was too nervous to talk to me. First off, Im like 5'4 and not gonna hurt anyone so don't be too nervous. Second, Im quite cuddly. Im a big softie, until a car tries to run me off the road. One thing speakers tend to do is bunch up with other speakers. It's a natural thing. Most of us are friends and this is a way for us to hang out, catch up, and chill. Don't think for a second it's some sort of secret club. We are just people too! Just say hey, if Im busy working on something I will tell you, but generally nothing is too pressing for me to do that. </p>
<p>A pro tip for me: bring whiskey or a bike and we are instant besties.</p>
<h3>Take a day and explore the city you are in.</h3>
<p>One of the reasons I love speaking is it's a fun way to travel. I've gotten to see some awesome cities: Minneapolis, Portland, DC, Miami, and soon Austin. There is so much to see and do in these cities that I try my hardest now to either plan a day trip or take an extra day to see things. My current thing is renting a bike and riding around the city. I get to get some new Strava PRs hopefully, see the city from a fun way, and interact with the residents! If you can't stay an extra day, dip out on one of the after parties and go exploring! The conference will be there when you get back, and you get to have a cool experience. </p>
<p>If you are in DC for a conference, try to take 2 days and just explore some of the 19 Smithsonian Museums. They are all free, and cover a wide range of topics from American History to Aviation History to African American History and so much more. I could easily spend 3 days in the Air and Space Museum alone.</p>
<h3>Come to the conference with an uncon talk.</h3>
<p>A lot of conferences have an uncon, a space where anyone can speak. People use it as a way to demo a talk and see what the reaction is, or use it to practice their speaking skills. It's a great way to get into speaking without the pressure of really speaking. A lot of conferences will add it to the ratings site, which gets you two things: a track record for other conferences to see and also some feedback (hopefully).</p>
<h3></h3>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/conference-speaking</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/conference-speaking" />
    <title>Conference Speaking</title>
    <published>2018-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">It wasn&#039;t in my plans to be a keynoter this year, or ever, but here we are. Im happy to say I will be one of the keynote speakers of
MidwestPHP, my talk being about mental health and how I&#039;ve learned to adapt and overcome challenges. Hopefully
people......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>It wasn't in my plans to be a keynoter this year, or ever, but here we are. Im happy to say I will be one of the keynote speakers of
<a href="https://midwestphp.org">MidwestPHP</a>, my talk being about mental health and how I've learned to adapt and overcome challenges. Hopefully
people will leave this talk with some ideas they can adapt to their lives as well. Based on a thread from Phil Sturgeon, depression can strike
anyone at anytime no matter who you are. Very timely. </p>
<p>Also, Im happy to say I will be giving a session at Midwest PHP going over the OpenAPI and how you can build your APIs with it. Its a fun talk and I love
giving it. Before that though, I will be in Miami to speak about Vue.js at <a href="https://sunshinephp.com">Sunshine</a>. Why I submitted on JS I dont know, but
Im having fun with it. Im recycling the API I built for CascadiaPHP to build a front end with Vue, which gives me more material for Midwest as well.</p>
<p>Im sure I will end up at other conferences but so far these are sure fire things. Other things I hope to accomplish soon: </p>
<ul>
<li>Launch the new PHPVersions. It will be built on PHP instead of Jekyll. Im hoping to take better advantage of automation and APIs to make this project
more robust. I also plan on publishing an OpenAPI spec to go along with it so others can consume the data. </li>
<li>Launch a personal finance blog. It's no secret I've been trying to learn everything I can about about personal finance and investing, both things
I wasn't taught much about in school or my early life. I hope this project helps others, especially developers making an insane amount of money make
smart choices. </li>
<li>Launch a photography blog. My last little project will be a photography blog. I got a camera this year and it's been a lot of fun going downtown to take pictures.
It would be great to see if I can turn it into a side business but right now its just fun. </li>
</ul>
<p>Hope to see you around at a conference next year!</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://matthewtrask.net/blog/cool-stuff-in-the-community</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://matthewtrask.net/blog/cool-stuff-in-the-community" />
    <title>Who is doing cool stuff in the community?</title>
    <published>2018-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Matt Trask</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Our community is full of amazing people creating and doing amazing things. I want to start a series where we highlight these people. 

If you haven&#039;t seen it yet, Beachcasts is a new streaming series from Adam Culp. If you don&#039;t know, Adam doesn&#039;t stop.......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Our community is full of amazing people creating and doing amazing things. I want to start a series where we highlight these people. </p>
<h3>Beachcasts</h3>
<p>If you haven't seen it yet, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCsOSGYawy8MG9Mh8NKgRHZQ">Beachcasts</a> is a new streaming series from <a href="https://twitter.com/adamculp">Adam Culp</a>. If you don't know, Adam doesn't stop. He runs SoFloPHP, the user group for people in South Florida, and also runs one of my favorite conferences: <a href="https://sunshinephp.com">Sunshine PHP</a>. With Beachcasts, Adam takes us through creating something I love, REST APIs, using a few tools that aren't generally at the forefront of the conversation. </p>
<p>Using Zend Expressive and Doctrine ORM, he walks through the steps needed to create a REST API. The best part is he doesn't shy away from a topic that most developers don't skip: <a href="https://apievangelist.com/2014/01/07/what-is-a-hypermedia-api/">Hypermedia</a>. The videos tend to be around 20 minutes, perfect for a lunch break, or something to watch before bed  and with Adam's style, its a very approachable way to watch another developer do work. </p>
<h3>Astrocasts</h3>
<p>Another streaming series which has been around for a while now is <a href="https://astrocasts.com">Astrocasts</a>. Friend of the blog <a href="https://twitter.com/beausimensen">Beau Simensen</a> started this series a few months ago and its been absolutely fun watching him work through building chat bots and apps with Symfony. As someone who uses Laravel in my spare time, watching other developers work with different frameworks gives me both insight into their flow and also an appreciation for others hard work. </p>
<p>Beau broadcasts a couple of times a week, and loves to engage with people watching via comments. It's an absolutely fun time, I enjoy putting it on while I finish up work, or watch the late night edition (the joys of being an hour behind him). Check it out, because its free knowledge for you to consume!</p>
<h3>Nikita Popov</h3>
<p>Most of us think <a href="https://twitter.com/nikita_ppv">Nikita</a> is probably a robot hidden away in the depths of a warehouse. He is an absolute machine who cranks out RFC's for our language and deserves a lot of recognition for his hard work. To help him, <a href="https://jetbrains.com">JetBrains</a> hired him for the purpose of allowing him to work on the core of PHP full time. Absolutely brilliant stuff on their part and makes me happy to be a paying subscriber to their products. </p>
<p>Of all the things he has done, one of the best things was picking up the work of previous developers and getting <a href="https://wiki.php.net/rfc/typed_properties_v2">typed properties</a> into the core language. With a vote of 70-1, it is one of the things bringing excitement to the release of 7.4 later this year. </p>
<h3>Matthieu Napoli</h3>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/matthieunapoli">Matthieu Napoli</a> is working on something that is quite intriguing. With the idea of serverless gaining momentum, PHP is not getting as much support as other languages. Matthieu saw this as an opportunity and creted <a href="https://bref.sh">Bref</a>. I haven't completely jumped on the hypetrain of serverless yet, but following Matthieu's work has been really fun. He clearly has found a way to fill a void in our ecosystem and is doing great work. When I do come around to serverless, this will be my first stop. Bref is a fantastic resource from the looks of it, and I can't wait to see what happens with it!</p>
<h3>Closing</h3>
<p>I hope to continue this type of post every so often. Our community is filled with an amazing amount of talented developers, each deserving of recognition. If you know someone you think deserves it, shoot me a message on twitter and when I write up my next post I will absolutely include them! </p>
<p>Cheers!</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
    </feed>
